[MUSIC]
My name is May Lee Koo, and I'm a designer and an inventor.
So some of the things I've designed have been an apple and now I design products for kids to use
so that they can have an easier time in school.
My other jobs include DJ.
and dancing.
they realized that it had to perform four different tasks.
It would need to take input, store information,
product information,
it and then output the results. Now this might sound simple but these four things
are common to all computers. That's what makes
a computer, a computer.
First we're going to talk about input.
This is my favorite because what input is, is the stuff that the world does or that you
do that makes the computer do stuff.
You can tell a computer what to do with a keyboard.
You can tell the computer what to do with a keyboard.
what to do with the mouse, the microphone, the camera, and now if you're wearing a computer
on your wrist, it might listen to your heartbeat or in your car, it might be listening to
what the car is doing.
doing and a touch screen can actually sense your finger and it takes that as input on
what it's doing.
All these different inputs give a computer information which is then stored in memory.
A computer's processor takes information from memory.
It manipulates it or changes it using an algorithm, which is just a series of commands, and then
it sends the process information back to be stored in memory again.
This can take a while to get the information stored.
until the processed information is ready to be output.
How a computer outputs information
depends on what the computer is designed to do. A computer display can show text, photos,
videos, or interactive games, even virtual reality. The output of a computer may even
even includes signals to control a robot.
And when computers connect over the internet,
the output from one computer becomes the input to another,
and vice versa.
But across all computers, regardless of the different types of technology they use, they're
always doing the same four things.
They take in information, they store it as data, and they're all doing the same thing.
data, they process it, and then they output the results.